Guide to the Ernest Shephard papers, 1939-1950 MS0248.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ernest Shephard papers
1939-1950
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Shephard, Ernest
MS0248.UA
3.5 Linear Feet
Ernest Sewall Shephard was a member of the George Washington University faculty from 1926 to 1966. Dr. Shephard was Professor of English holding the Master of Arts degree. He chaired the English Department for many years. Collection includes correspondence, articles papers, English class notes, lectures, and other items from Ernest Shephard. The materials range from 1939-50.
Box 5
Box 6
Box 7
Box 1
Box 2
Box 3
Box 4
Acquisition Information
Provenance of collection is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
Ernest Sewall Shephard was a member of the George Washington University faculty from 1926 to 1966. Dr. Shephard was Professor of English holding the Master of Arts degree. He chaired the English Department for many years.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in the collection include correspondence, articles papers, English class notes, lectures, and other items from Ernest Shephard. The materials range from 1939-50.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Education; Biography; English; Courses and lectures; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University; Shephard, Ernest
- Personal Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Patent, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photography, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- English D. The Novel, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- English 14. Machiavelli's The Prince, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Truth And Beauty E 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Seminar In Restoration Comedy 1676-1680, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Abandoned Souls E 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Better Half E 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- English 46 Book #1 And #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- English 45 Book #1 And #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- English 9 Book #1 And #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Disobedient, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Columbus Sees His Circle E 9; Deliverance E 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Burglary A La Mode, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bread Upon The Water, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- The Plain Gold Band, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Involuntary Proselyter; The Fall Of The Dynasty; In And Out The Chimney, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Piece of String (Criticism), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Night Air, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miniature Anthology of Contemporary Verse, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Milly, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Master of his Destiny, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Little Red Riding Hood, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- English 48, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Such Stuff As Dreams Are Made On or Jean, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- To Err Is Human; Traffic (An Essay); The Third Degree, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The Recovery of Eben Trask, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Reading of Poetry: A Virtue Or A Vice E 9, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Puppy Love; Professional Call, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- The Presidential Campaign Of 1904, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The Appearance Of Sentimentalism In Restoration Comedy, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Restoration Drama, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Jurgen Visits Verona; Little Myths, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Truth About The Cherry Tree, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Rhetorics And Brown Derbies, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Remarks, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Rabelais, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Satire, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Poetry, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous II: Drama General, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous II: Education, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous II: Christmas Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous II: Correspondence with Students, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- English 92 (European Lit.), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Lectures and Outlines, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Survey: Undergraduate Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- English 91 (Lectures), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- English 91 (Lectures), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- English 51, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- English 51, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- English 91, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Literary Crit., undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- English 51, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Biography, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Types: Lectures, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- English 91-92 (Outline Of Course), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- English 52 Exams, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- English 52 Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- English 152 (Shelley), undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Lucretius Questions, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Reorganization of Columbian College, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Freshman Composition, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- English 92 (Dante), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Renaissance, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- English 92 (Roland), undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
- English 92 (Spanish Lit.- Cervantes), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- English 92 (Philosophers), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Department, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  General note
  Spring
- George Meredith, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Drama 91 I, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- English 91 (Classic Epics), undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Drama 91 II, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- English 92 (Njal's Saga), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Drama 91 III, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- English 92 Exams, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Outlines, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Neo-Classicism, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- English 151 (Romantic Movement), undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Types Of European Lit., undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Lectures, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 2)